以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
我们准备好了
so are we ready to go
关于18065的任何问题，所以它将如此
any questions on 1806 5 so it will be as
我之前说过线性的混合物
I said before a mixture of linear
代数和数学问题
algebra and math questions along with
在线使用这些材料，所以我在
online using the material ok so I'm in
这第一个星期或两个审查
this first week or two reviewing the
线性代数的亮点，我
highlights of linear algebra and I've
达到这一点要记得那么好
reached this point to remember well so
我刚才说了两句话
we I just said two words about
使用列乘以矩阵
multiplying matrices by using column
时间行作为一种方式来做到现在
times row as a as a way to do it and now
我想通过五个来说明这一点
I want to illustrate that by the five
矩阵的关键因子分解是可以的
key factorizations of matrices okay so
他们是什么，你认识他们
what are they and do you recognize them
事实上每个人都使用这些字母
everybody uses those letters in fact
这些字母中的一些像卢或
those some of those letters like lu or
QR将是最常用的matlab
QR would be the most used matlab
线性代数中的命令所以是四月路
commands in linear algebra so a April Lu
我可能会说一些我会发展的东西
I'll maybe say something I'll develop
今天，但它是关于消除
today but it's about elimination
求解线性系统，这样总是
solving linear systems so that's always
线性代数课程的开始但是
the start of a linear algebra course but
我会快速到这里，我只是想
I it will go fast here I just want to
告诉你一个不同的方式来到L
show you a different way to get to L
你将三角形时间降低到上部
times u lower triangular times upper
三角形可能你已经看过了
triangular probably you've seen that
那些三角矩阵你知道吗？
those triangular matrices so do you know
QR是关于这些方块的QR是什么
what QR is what's QR about these squares
是分解的重要应用
is the big application the factorization
那么什么样的矩阵才能得到它
so what kind of a matrix gets that
字母Q正交列
letter Q orthogonal the columns are
正交常常是正交的
orthogonal often orthonormal so
正交意味着它们是垂直的
orthogonal means they're perpendicular
彼此和/或正常的手段
to each other and or so normal means
它们是单位向量，所以就是这样
they're unit vectors so that that is so
所以Q经常代表一个矩阵
so Q often represents a matrix with
正交列，所以你我们可以
orthonormal columns so so you we could
如果你想记住，请说克施密特
say gram-schmidt if you want to remember
几个老人谁的
a couple of old-timers who whose
算法产生Q和R怎么样
algorithm produces Q and R how about
这个真的是中心的一个
this one this is really a central one in
数学纯数学应用数学无处不在
math pure math applied math everywhere
应用程序所以S代表对称
applications so S stands for symmetric
所以这是一个特殊的因素分析
so this is a special factorization for
对称矩阵，你可以看到
symmetric matrices and you can see that
它是对称的这个lambda是
it's symmetric this lambda is the
对角特征值矩阵总是lambda
diagonal eigenvalue matrix always lambda
对于4ighen值
for 4i ghen values
q当然就像那个q不同的q
q is like that q different q of course
那你可以找到一些公正的
that q you can find sort of just
从革兰氏施密特直截了当这
straight forward from gram-schmidt this
所涉及的具有特征向量，所以你
q involved has the eigenvectors so you
没有一些没有找到特征向量
don't find eigenvectors without some
额外的工作还可以，这就是特征向量
extra work okay so that's eigenvectors
是啊所以这将是值得推广等等
yeah so that would be worth expanding so
这里的特征向量
here are the eigenvectors of
他们在这里规范化了矩阵sn2
of the matrix sn2 them normalized here
是特征值lambda1到lambdan
are the eigenvalues lambda 1 to lambda n
现在这里是特征向量
and here are the eigenvectors now
换位好吧让我想起了
transposed okay so remind me of the
我猜一个关于两个事实的重大事实
great fact about two facts I guess one
其实关于特征值和一个事实
fact about the eigenvalues and one fact
关于特征向量这就像一个
about the eigenvectors this is like an
线性声明中的重要事实
important fact in a statement in linear
代数什么是我们所知道的
algebra what is what do we know about
特征向量哦，我想我是
the eigenvectors oh well i guess i'm
放弃它
giving it away
特征向量是正交的
the eigenvectors are orthogonal that's
很重要
very important
很好地制作一些矩阵
make some matrices well they're
美丽的矩阵他们是国王
beautiful matrices they're the kings of
线性代数Q是我的王后
linear algebra Q's are the queens in my
看来正交矩阵是
opinion orthogonal matrices are the
对称矩阵的皇后是
queens of symmetric matrices are the
国王所以这些都是正交的
king so so these are orthonormal
特征向量和关键点
eigenvectors and the key point an
这里暗示的重点是
important point that's implicit here is
他们中有n个是完整的
there are n of them there's a complete
设置矩阵可以对角化和
set the matrix can be diagonalized and
那些有关的特别之处
those well what's special about the
特征值其他矩阵可以是Q.
eigenvalues other matrices could be Q
lambdaQ转置但对称
lambda Q transpose but symmetric
矩阵是额外的东西
matrices are something additional about
拉姆达所以他们都真正使本征
lambda so they're all real so eigen
值是真实的，而特征向量是
values are real and eigen vectors are
正交可以选择正交
orthonormal can be chosen orthonormal
可以选择我只需说好了
can be chosen I just have to say okay
好的好哦现在也许我会用
good good good oh now maybe I'll use
作为矩阵的一个例子
that as an example of matrix
乘法，所以让我做
multiplication so let me just do that
这里简单的矩阵乘法但是
here simple matrix multiplications but
它使QlambdaQ成为重点
it makes the point so Q lambda Q
换位好吧我的观点是什么
transpose okay well what was my point
关于矩阵乘法让我成为
about matrix multiplication let me be
这真的涉及两个矩阵我
it really involved two matrices here I
不幸的是有三个，所以我会
unfortunately have three so I'm gonna
必须用其中一个来挤压lambda
have to squeeze lambda in with one of
这些立方体也很好地看作两个
the cubes too to see it nicely as two
矩阵，所以他们只是那样做那里
matrices so they just do that yeah there
现在我已经制作了两个很简单的矩阵
now I've made two matrices that was easy
好吧现在是什么规则和在
okay now what's the rule and in the
首先注意到这是一个，这是B
first notes this was a and this was B
当你乘以两个矩阵时
and when you multiply two matrices the
规则是这是Qlambda的列
rule is this is columns of Q lambda
时间行Q转置我是
times rows of Q transpose I'm
按行乘以列，所以它是
multiplying columns by rows and so it's
列向量乘以行向量和
a column vector times a row vector and
这给了我们一个矩阵，所以每个都是
that gives us a matrix so each and it's
这是一个特殊的矩阵
a special matrix what so this is a
列这是一行，当我乘以
column this is a row and when I multiply
n乘以1乘以n得到N乘n
n by 1 times 1 by n I get an N by n
矩阵，这是非常特殊和什么
matrix and it's pretty special and what
是我的一个特殊事实
is the special fact about I'm sort of
从上次回忆起
recalling from last time
列的时间有什么特别之处
what's special about a column times a
排它的等级是特殊的，它的等级是1
row it's rank is special it's rank is 1
它的所有列空间都是唯一的
it all its column space well the only
列周围是这一列所有列
column around is this one so all columns
所有行都是这个家伙的倍数
are multiples of this guy all rows are
我们可以看到这个家伙的倍数
multiples of this guy as we could see
从一个例子，他们只是做一个
from an example so they just do an
示例12次34随机取
example 1 2 times 3 4 to take a random
例如使得将给予我们3468
example so that would give us 3 4 6 8
我确信这些专栏是
I'm sure enough the columns are
1的倍数是行的倍数
multiples of 1 2 the rows are multiples
34和等级是1好等所以那些
of 3 4 and the rank is 1 okay so those
是我想要的构建块
are the building blocks now I want to
建立一些东西，所以我们去，所以这是
build something so here we go so this is
一些等级的总和
a sum of rank some
秩1的总和列时间排，所以我
of Rank 1 sum of column times row so I
第1列第1行是我的
take column 1 times Row 1 that's my
总和中的第一件事就是第1列
first thing in the sum so column 1 of
这让你看到我只好潜行
that so you see I had to sneak the
lambda结束只有两个因素
lambda end to have just just two factors
那么Qlambda的第1列是什么哦
so what's column 1 of Q lambda oh that's
一个好问题
a good question
所以Q的第1列是第1个Q1
so column 1 of Q is Q 1 the first
特征向量，但现在我正在乘以
eigenvector but now I I'm multiplying by
这个对角线矩阵你看到你的
this diagonal matrix do you see in your
记住Qlambda的第一列是什么
mind what's the first column of Q lambda
想想那一秒就这样吧
just think about that a second so here's
我们可以窃取任何小角落
we can steal any little corner for for
对于一个矩阵，所以这里是Q1和
for a matrix ok so here's Q 1 and the
其余的列然后在这里
rest of the columns and then here's
lambda1和那个Qlambda所以我是
lambda 1 and that's Q lambda so I'm
将这些放在一起，我问
putting those together and I'm asking
什么是答案的第一列
what's the first column of the answer
你看它是如何工作
and you see how that works
它是Q1lambda1恰好是lambda1
it's Q 1 lambda 1 exactly that lambda 1
将Q1乘以其他lambda
will multiply Q 1 these other lambdas
乘以后面的列，所以第一个
multiplied later columns so the first
列是λ-1次，Q1右所以
column is lambda 1 times Q 1 right so
那是第一个lambda1Q1的人
that's it's the first guy lambda 1 Q 1
然后第一行将是Q.
and then the first row of this will be Q
1转置那是我们的第一个人
1 transpose that's the first guy in our
N物的总和，让我把下一个
sum of N Things and let me put the next
一个在最后1拉姆达2Q2Q2
one in the last 1 lambda 2 Q 2 Q 2
转置和lambdanqnQN转置
transpose and lambda n qn QN transpose
这真的是一种很好的写作方式
that's really a nice way to write to
分解产品QlambdaQ.
break up the product Q lambda Q
转置这称为谱
transpose this is called the spectral
定理，这是对称的s
theorem so that's the symmetric that's s
那就是那样的
that's s there is that so that's the
我们已经分成了一个等级
we've broken up s into rank one pieces
这就像一个不变的主题和
that's that's like a constant theme and
这些写一件很特别
these write one pieces are quite special
因为它们是对称的Q1Q1
because they're symmetric Q 1 Q 1
转置将是对称的哦哦
transpose will be symmetric and oh so
我们可以这么说吧
can we so so let's just
我遵循乘法规则
I follow the rule for multiplying
矩阵，但也许我可以检查
matrices but maybe I could just check
这就是它来到了正确的事情
that it's the right thing that it came
对了，所以我的意思是通过检查
out right so what do I mean by checking
我想我只会检查一下Q次
I guess I'll just check about s times Q
1这样看，如果这件事情倍
1 so look at if this thing times the
第一个特征向量，我得到了什么
first eigenvector and what do I get
好的，所以你会喜欢这个，所以我有
ok so you'll like this so there's I've
分裂s转换的等级1片之和
split up s into a sum of Rank 1 pieces
分裂是你看到了一切
and that splitting is you see it all
它真的告诉你什么
over it's really showing you what the
对称矩阵的碎片是和
pieces of the symmetric matrix are and
现在我要检查那是不是
now I'm just gonna check that that's a
正确的s公式正确，所以我会
correct correct formula for s so I'll
将它乘以Q1，我希望得到
multiply it by Q 1 and I'm hoping to get
正确的事，我实际上是什么
the right thing and what do I actually
如果我成倍增加这整个业务
get if I multiply this whole business
次Q1我得到lambda1Q1Q1
times Q 1 I get lambda 1 Q 1 Q 1
转移那是第一个人的时代
transpose that's the first guy times by
Q1加右我将它乘以Q.
Q 1 plus right I'm multiplying this by Q
1，这第一个词给了我那个和
1 and this first term gave me that and
什么是下学期给我放放
what does the next term give me put put
我出于我的痛苦，这就是我
me out of my misery here it's uh I'm
寻找这个简化的东西
looking for this thing to simplify like
疯了，那么第二个任期是什么时候
mad okay so what's the second term when
我
I'm
通过q1供给这个家伙我得到什么零
supply this guy by q1 what do I get zero
这是正确的，这是我们想要的和
that's right that's what we want and
当我把最后一个人乘以q1时，我得到了
when I multiply the last guy by q1 I get
因为Q是正交所以这个
0 because the Q's are orthogonal so this
就是我得到的
is all I get
然后我不需要这个加号
and then so I don't need this plus
这就是它，然后我能做些什么
anymore that's it and then what can I do
以改进或者是一点点
to improve that or is that a little
有点重复的公式
somewhat repetitive formula for the
回答我最后想做什么
answer what do I want to do finally I
想要记住Q是
want to remember that the Q's are
归一化他们的单位向量那么
normalized their unit vectors so what
确实，在这里告诉我一个主
does that tell me here to one principal
q1转置时间Q1这就是什么
q1 transpose times Q 1 this is just what
它就是这样，这就是规范化意味着什么
it sits so that's what normalized means
长度的平方是长度
that the length squared is the length
矢量平方的长度和
the length of the vector squared and
它是1所以我可以取消那个词而且我是
it's 1 so I can cancel that term and I'm
得到正确的答案，这就是我
getting the right answer that's all I
所有这一切都与我有关
that's all this was about I was just
检查并想看看它会如何
checking and wanted to see how it would
掉下来和它属于正确的是
fall out and it falls right out that
这个公式是正确的矩阵
this formula is the correct matrix s
因为它有正确的特征向量
because it's got the right eigenvectors
qs，它有正确的特征值
qs and it's got the right eigenvalues
lambda所以它必须是正确的
lambda so it's got to be the right
矩阵是的，这就像一个
matrix yes is that ok that's a like a
第一个例子看看这个如何分裂
first example to see how this splitting
进入排名，让你回到你的身上
into rank ones gives you back what you
期待足够的它给你
expect easily enough it gives you the
信息您预计好了，这就是
information you expect okay so that's
对称特征值图片
the symmetric eigen value picture for
对称矩阵，我们会看到它
symmetric matrices and we'll see it
再次，这五个都很好
again it's it's well all five of these
很重要我不知道是否重要
are big are important I don't know if
你知道这个
you know this
但它将成为一个基础
but it's going to be a foundational
分解这门课程和
factorization for this course and for
所有的数据科学你知道吗？
all of data science do you know it's
如此命名首先是什么意思
named so what does it mean first of all
只是对此进行评论然后
just just a comment on this and then
我们会把它保存几个星期
we'll save it for a couple of weeks so
这个U实际上是一个正交矩阵
this U is actually an orthogonal matrix
V也是如此，它有两个
and so is V so it has it has two
正交矩阵这就是人们的原因
orthogonal matrices so that's why people
称他们为U和V而不是q1和
called them U and V rather than q1 and
q2就像太多了
q2 which was like too much just get
下标如此正交对角线
subscripts so orthogonal times diagonal
时间正交让我说正交
times orthogonal let me say orthogonal
对角线或声波图和1806将作为
diagonal or sonogram and 1806 would as
现在达到这个主题因为它是
of now reach this topic because it's
跳起来的重要性，它被称为
jumped up in importance and it's called
奇异值分解以及那些
singular value decomposition well those
很长的单词或每个人都称它为
are long words or everybody calls it the
SVD奇异值分解
SVD the singular value decomposition
重点是它的工作原理
the point is it's it's the it works for
每个矩阵矩形矩阵
every matrix rectangular matrices
它没有足够的问题
there's no issue of does it have enough
特征向量与否这是一个问题
eigenvectors or not that's an issue here
这不是每个矩阵都是一个问题
well it's an issue here not every matrix
有足够的特征向量来做到这一点
has got enough eigenvectors to make that
为每个工作的矩阵工作，因为
work every matrix that one works because
而不是一组特征向量
instead of one set of eigenvectors it's
得到两个矩阵两个不同的集合
got two matrices two different sets of
奇异向量哦，我们会我们会看到，
singular vectors oh we'll we'll see that
这一点很重要没关系
that's that's important okay
所以这真的很快
so that's a that's really a quick
基本因素分析的概述
overview of fundamental factorizations
而且我想再说一句话
and I'd like to say just another word
关于消除一个平等的然后
about elimination a equal Lu and then
我们会离开它息事宁人
we'll leave it leave it alone
所以消除是的，你还记得吗？
so elimination yeah do you remember that
首先是线性的开始
that first the beginning of linear
当你解决ax等于B时的代数
algebra when you're solving ax equal B
你做这些行操作
you do these row operations
我可以说我想说的就是全部
can I just what I want to say is all
那些你操作的行操作
those row operations that you that you
L次U完美表达了
do are perfectly expressed by L times U
所以这是1806年的一个关键点
and so that that's a key point in 1806
但我有不同的方式来看待它
but I have a different way to look at it
这就是我想告诉你的
so that's what I wanted to show you I
有一个我想告诉你一个等级的总和
have a I want to show you a sum of rank
它适合的是一个行时间列
one's a row times column it fits in
今天所以我只是想知道为什么
today so so I just like to see why does
矩阵可逆这是一个正方形
a matrix invertible this is a square
矩阵现在和可逆的因素
matrix now and invertible and it factors
如果一切顺利的消除和
if all goes well with elimination and
枢轴非零
the pivots are nonzero
它会影响较低的三角形时间
it factors into lower triangular times
上三角，这是关键的一步
upper triangular so that's a key step
这就是MATLAB会做的事情
that that is that MATLAB would do with
lvo事件会产生这两个
lvo event would produce those two
现在因素我想在一个
factors now I want to do them in a
列时间排的方式我只是
column times row way which I just
意识到很晚才有一个整洁的方式
realized late was there was a neat way
要做到这一点，我可以采取矩阵，做
to do it so can I take a matrix and do
消除我的矩阵有多大
elimination how big a matrix shall I
拿两个你说你三个
take two by two you say you three by
三个人完全不相信
three somebody not convinced totally by
两两
two by two
让我两个一个地做，然后如果你
let me do it two by two and then if you
想要，如果你真的想要一个三乘三
want if you really want a three by three
黄色，我会这样做，这是两个两个
yellow I'll do it okay here's two by two
两个四个三七怎么样就可以了
two four three seven how's that okay so
什么是耶，所以让我们记住什么
what is yeah so let's remember what
消除确实
elimination does
它从中减去该行的倍数
it subtracts a multiple of that row from
那一个得到两到三个和
that one to get two to three and the
多是二，因此挖空
multiple is two so it knocks out the
四个两三或六个所以它留下1
four two threes or six so it leaves a 1
我们是哦，是的，谢谢你允许我
and we're oh yeah thanks for allowing me
做两个两个
to do two by two
我已经完成了，我已经达到了
I've already done it now I've reached
你是这样的，这是你的上层
you so here's a and here's you the upper
三角形的家伙与枢轴上
triangular guy with the pivots on the
对角好，然后问题是
diagonal good and then the question is
用矩阵语言表达那一步
express that step in matrix language and
正确答案是L次你所以
the right answer is L times u so the
正确的答案是，这是一个
right answer is that this that this a is
所以我会删掉那封U是L的字母
so I'll just erase that letter U is L
你是什​​么LL所以LL更低
times u so what is L L is the lower
三角形的家伙，它有它
triangular guy and it has there the
你在这里使用过的数字是什么
number that you used here and what was
我减去了那一行中的两行
that I subtracted two of that row from
这让我想有这样就会
this so I wanted to there so that would
我会称之为乘数我
be I would call that a multiplier I
乘行一个由两个中减去
multiplied Row one by two subtracted to
得到零和两个两个
get that zero and for a two by two
例子我现在完成好了我想要的
example I was finished okay now I want
看到这所以有L次ü什么
to see this so there's L times U what
发生了我想看看L次
happened I would like to see how L times
你从这一行出来一列时间
u comes out of this row a column times
因此让我开始让我再想一想
row so let me start let me think again
真正的重点是什么呢
what so the really the point of
消除我们为什么这样做的原因
elimination what was why did we do this
首先
in the first place
因为在这里我们有两个耦合
because here we had two coupled
方程式他们是我们的一对夫妇
equations they were a couple together we
无法立即解决这一步
couldn't solve them instantly that step
消除
of elimination
在这个角落给我两个下来
juice me two down here in this corner
一个方程式，我已经消除了
one equation that I've eliminated the
第一个未知的X来自第二个等式
first unknown X from the second equation
所以第二个等式是零X加1
so the second equation is zero X plus 1
y等于右手边，我解决了
y equal right hand side and I solve it
马上好的
immediately okay
那我是怎么一个接一个的呢
so how did I get to that one by one
这些家伙的问题删除得很好
problem with these guys removed well
是的，我可以在这里写下我的
yeah just right can I write here the my
通过并行方式把它在两份
parallel way to think of it in it two by
两个很小我承认没关系
two is pretty small I admit okay
所以我开始用两个三四七我
so I start with two three four seven I
我希望将它分成两部分
want to split it in two I want to get
第一行和第一列
the first row and column in one piece
东西去了另一块
something goes there and the other piece
东西有好
is something there okay
这就是淘汰做了什么
that's what elimination has done it's
采取原始矩阵分裂
taken the original matrix its splitted
这些都是排名第一，所以我们只是
these are both ranked one so let's just
首先你可以告诉我发生了什么
first of all you could tell me what goes
在第一级的那个空白区域
in that blank space in the first rank
一个矩阵所以我可以这样说
one matrix so what can I say this in
消除第一阶段的话
words the first stage of elimination
脱离一个是一个很大的矩阵
pulls off from a so a is some big matrix
从它考虑到它拉出来
it pulls off from a it takes account of
第一列和第一列就这样吧
the first column and row so it it it
在这里写一个我们作为第一列
writes a as here we go as a first column
说第1列第1行加上简单
say column 1 Row 1 plus plus the easy
部分简单部分将是一个矩阵
part the easy part will be a matrix with
那里全零，哦，这里和那里零
all zeros there Oh zeroes there and here
我有一个2
I have a 2
我可以称之为-这是我现在的方式
can I call it a - this is my way now to
想想消除真的是什么
think about what elimination is really
这样做是从N到n开始的
doing it's starting with an N by n
矩阵它排名第一
matrix it's pulling off a rank one
获得该列的矩阵
matrix which has gets that column and
那行是正确的，它得到了它
that row correct and it gets whatever it
在这里，然后剩下的是什么
has in here and then the rest of what's
在那里-你看到我们已经完成了
in there is a - you see that we've done
这里第一步得到了第一步
that here the first step got the first
行和列是正确的，如果它是排名
row and column correct and if it's rank
一个数字是六六和六
one what number goes there six six and
那么剩下这就是我们
then this is the rest this is what we
有一个小尺寸的工作和它
have one size smaller to work on and it
看起来已经是七六了
looks like it was seven six has been
使用它是一个我真正想要的
used so it's a one that's really I want
认为这秩一个矩阵作为的
to think of this rank one matrix as the
的第一行L次的第一列
first column of L times the first row of
你和那个家伙是第二列
U and then this guy is the second column
L次第二排U我没事
of L times the second row of U I'm okay
我还没有提出这方面的证据在
I haven't presented this proof in the
之前和之前的课程是两个一个的
class before and for two-by-two it's
对我来说看起来有点矫枉过正，我的意思是
looking like overkill to me I mean like
为什么你不必做那么深的事
why you don't have to do all that deep
想要得到碎片，但我的
thinking to get to get pieces but my
想法是它给出了细分和
idea is that it gives the breakdown and
这当然是我们的专栏时间
this of course is by our column times
行规则是Lu所以我们就是这样
row rule that's Lu so we're we're
开始和我们打破它
starting with a and we're breaking it up
入路，其中路的第一块路的
into Lu where Lu the first piece of Lu
是第一列时间然后是行
is the first column times row and then
接下来的部分是剩下的部分
the next pieces are the rest of the
矩阵
matrix
虽然在下一个被打破了
and though was get broken down the next
如果我，消除的阶段会破裂
stage of elimination would break if I
这个阶段有一个3x3的剥离了
had a 3x3 this stage peeled off the
行中的第一列然后是下一阶段
first column in row then the next stage
将剥离第二个新的第二个
would peel off the second the new second
行和第三阶段的列
column in row and the third stage would
在排第三列就在去年
have the third column in rows just last
pivot对你有意义
pivot does this make any sense to you
你可以给我发电子邮件，并说它不是那样的
you could email me and say it's not that
很棒，但我认为这是看到的
great but I think it's to see that the
消除的最终结果是L次U.
final result of elimination is L times U
是不是有一点魔力呢？
is it's there's a little magic in in
看看你在做什么，我想
seeing what you're doing and I think
这是一种了解你正在做什么的方法
this is a way to see what you're doing
你是第一个剥离的人
that you're you're peeling off a first
部分留下第二部分
part to leave a second part like that
然后第二部分你会剥离
then the second part you would peel off
第二列乘以第二行
the second column times the second row
可以通过枢轴来划分它
may be divided by the pivot to make it
这是正确的，那将是
correct and that would that would put
在盒子的其余部分和
something in the rest of the box and
然后三个将是剩下的
then a three would be the rest of that
盒子好吧我在这里停下来我很高兴你
box okay I'm stopping here I'm glad you
让我做2x2因为我看到3x3会
let me do 2x2 since I see that 3x3 would
它会毁了一天呀还好一
it would have ruined the day yeah okay a
问题还是让我停下来一分钟，以便
question or let me pause for a minute so
我已经谈过这些因素
I've talked about these factorizations
这一次，我们不会再看到这一块我们
this one we won't see again this one we
我们会看到很棒的时间
will see big-time and this one we will
而这一个我们会，是的，是的
and this one we will yeah yeah
235是我们真正的那些
2 3 & 5 are the ones that we're really
会看到很多问题或想法
gonna see a lot of questions or thoughts
或者好吧我想我现在想告诉你
or okay I guess I want to tell you now
完成今天的前进
to complete today's moving forward in
这个问题的基本定理
this subject the fundamental theorem of
线性代数的基本定理
linear algebra the fundamental theorem
线性代数的好做好准备或
of linear algebra okay ready for that or
你可能已经看过了，因为
you may have seen it already because
它像的亮点
it's like the highlight of
这个主题的基本思想
of this subject of the basic ideas in
这个主题是正确的，然后也许我可以
this subject right and then maybe I can
之后我会告诉你那个定理的人
after I'd tell you that theorem people
世界各地给我发作作业
around the world send me homework
现在要做的问题你会想到任何问题
problems to do now you would think any
明智的教授永远不会那样做
sensible professor would never do those
他会说这是你的问题
problems like he would say it's your
问题，但我被带走了，我
problem but I get carried away and I
有时解决它们
solve them sometimes
所以一个人来自印度上周
so one came from India last week and it
涉及到基本定理
involved the fundamental theorem of
线性代数谁在那里教它
linear algebra whoever teaching it there
真的是在球上，我会
really was on on the ball and well I'll
之后告诉你那个问题
tell you that problem after after the
基本定理没关系
fundamental theorem okay
基本定理它大约四个
fundamental theorem it's about four
子空间所以我发明了四个名字
subspaces so I invented the name four
基本子空间，所以我可以列出
fundamental subspaces so can i list the
四个子空间基本基础我们
four subspaces fundamental basis well we
知道其中一个已经是专栏
know one of them already the column
空间所以对于矩阵我们给了一个
space so for a matrix we're given a
矩阵a表示M在等级R的末尾
matrix a that's M by end of rank R
这是我们的正常开始
that's our that's our normal starting
那么那四个子空间是什么呢？
point so what are those four subspaces
它们是如何相关的以及它们是什么相关的
and how are they related and what's
他们的维度和那些是什么
their dimension and what what those a
关键事实好吧我们已经知道了专栏
key fact okay we already know the column
矩阵的空间列空间和
space column space of the matrix and
实际上我们已经知道了行空间
actually we already know the row space
矩阵，我们有记号的
of a matrix and we have the notation for
转置的列空间和
that column space of a transpose and
什么是维度，所以这是
what is the dimension so that was the
任何人都在第一讲的关键点
key point in the first lecture anybody
谁错过了第一堂课应该去
who missed the first lecture should go
回到一点一点的笔记
back to the notes of one point one
对于该进入的思考
for the for the thinking that goes into
维度等于那些维度
the dimension equals what which of those
我想要的三个数字是
three numbers do I want to is the
列空间的维数是或和
dimension of the column space are or and
我能马上说些什么呢
what can I say about our right away
与M＆M相比，是的还是相等或者
compared to M&M yeah less or equal or
我能不能拥有更多的独立性
could I couldn't have more independent
列比我有列所以我有
columns than I have columns so I've got
n列，所以我们他们的
n columns so our our of them are
独立，所以我们在某个地方更少或
independent so our is somewhere less or
等于希望等于n
equal hopefully equal to n what about
行空间的维数有多少
the dimension of the row space how many
矩阵得到我们的独立行
independent rows as the matrix got our
谢谢你，这是一个伟大的事实
thank you that's that's the great fact
新证明减少了部分时间
with a new proof less time in section
1.1那些具有相同的维度
1.1 that those have the same dimension
相同的尺寸，你知道它
same dimension which is you know it's
你认为你看一个简单的好吧
you think okay you look at a simple
例如，这是真的，但你知道你是否
example it's true but you know if you if
你给了一个50的矩阵
you're given a matrix that's fifty by
百真正的事实，那些
hundred really the fact that those
百柱有相同数量的
hundred columns have the same number of
独立的那些50行
independent ones as those 50 rows that's
那个好像现在好了另一个
that's like great okay now the other
空格是矩阵的零空间
spaces are the null space of the matrix
在a和只是为了做一切
in of a and just to make everything
自然对称a的零空间
naturally symmetric a null space of a
转置那些是最后两个
transpose those are the last two those
是四个基本子空间
are the four fundamental subspaces which
你已经看过了，他们甚至都在
you've seen and they're even on the
线性代数教科书的封面
cover of the linear algebra textbook
好吧那么什么是零空间
okay so what's the null space
ax的解集等于零
the set of solutions to ax equals zero
权没有空间，所有的解决方案砍掉
right no space is all solutions to ax
等于e所以null空间有向量
equals e so the null space has vector
这些向量在XS中为零空间
these vectors in the XS the null space
不是从矩阵中取出的
isn't taken from the matrix the row of
列空间中的行空间
the row space in the column space those
这些数字都在矩阵中
those numbers are sitting in the matrix
null的空格和空格
the null space and the null space of a
transpose是null这个词的解决方案
transpose are solutions to the word null
反映出这是一个事实
is reflecting the fact that that's a
零，这就是它成为一个空间的原因
zero and that's what makes it a space
现在你可以让我问你
now can you just let me just ask you to
再想一想我说的时候隐含着什么
think again what's implied when I say
当我使用空间这个词的时候
when I use the word space a space of
矢量我可以添加是的
vectors I can add yeah
所以你我可以做最重要的事情
so so you I can do the most important
在该线性代数的操作
operations of linear algebra in that
我可以在这里添加两个向量让我
space I can add two vectors here let me
只需添加它们，所以在这里我将有一个向量
just add them so here I'll have a vector
X，让我再说一个a
X and let me say another another one a
矢量Y然后我做我另外跟着
vector Y then I do addition I follow the
规则我看到这可以写成
rules I see that this can be written as
斧子加y是零加零，因此你有什么
ax plus y is zero plus zero so what have
我知道如果X在，我已经知道了
I learned I've learned that if X is in
null空格和Y在null中
the null space and Y is in the null
空格然后X加y所以空格是
space then X plus y so the null space is
正如你所说的那样，我不去
as you said closed meaning I don't go
如果X在其中并且Y在其中，则在它之外
outside it if X is in it and Y is in it
然后总和在它和类似地从
then the sum is in it and similarly from
斧头等于零我得到一个C时代X
ax equals zero I get to a times C x
等于零
equals zero
它只是乘以C乘以C
it's just multiplied by C by a number C
那么这两个事实就意味着我可以
so those two facts that that means I can
做线性代数我可以乘
do linear algebra I can multiply by
数字，我可以添加换句话说我
numbers and I can add in other words I
可以采取
can take
线性组合就是你做的
linear combinations that's what you do
与向量和点是如果我这样做
with vectors and the point is if i do it
如果我采用两个零空间的组合
if i take combinations of two null space
球员我仍然在零空间好了，
guys I'm still in the null space okay so
这就是零空间的重点
that's the point of the null space and
现在好了，现在是基础的一部分
well now so now part of the fundamental
定理是要弄清楚有多少
theorem is to figure out how many
独立向量在null中
independent vectors are in the null
空间有多少独立解决方案
space how many solutions independent
解决方案做了那个方程组
solutions does that system of equations
有这么那将是维和我
have so that'll be the dimension and I
要问你什么是让我画
have to ask you what it is let me draw a
在你想到的时候想象一下
picture while you're thinking about
这些空间是梦幻般的有
those spaces it's fantastic to have
这些美丽干净的板好了，
these beautiful clean boards okay so
这是我的行空间行的图片
here's my picture of the row space rows
这是转置的列空间
that's the column space of a transpose
这是我的零空间图片
and here's my picture of the null space
一个，这是斧头的解决方案
of a and that's the solutions to ax
等于零，为什么我把这两个
equals zero and why have I put these two
和这两个在一起这样的
together and these two together so the
另一对将是列空间C
other pair will be the column space C of
转置的a和null空间就在那里
a and null space of a transpose so there
是他们的四个空间
are the four spaces where their
关系是基本定理
relationship is the fundamental theorem
线性代数所以首先是什么
of linear algebra so first of all what
对不起，所以我有一个M乘n矩阵
sorry so I have an M by n matrix so that
告诉我，我的行是一个典型的行
tells me that my rows a typical row has
n组件对我看一个Mbyn
n components right I look at an M by n
矩阵让我们做吧2×3
matrix let's do it two by three
矩阵，所以如果我看行空间
matrix so if I look at the row space
这是M，这是n所以我看到了
this is M and this is n so so I see
三个行具有长度3和
three the rows have length three and of
当然他们也乘以X的
course they multiply the X's which also
长度为3X1X2X3这就是原因
has length 3 X 1 X 2 X 3 that's why
这些都在一起，因为它们都是
these are together because they're both
在n维空间然后为什么
in n-dimensional space then why are
这些因为列是
these together because the columns are
在二维空间中
in two dimensional space for this
示例和转置的零空间
example and null space of a transpose
只是像y1y这两个组成部分
would be just two components like y 1 y
2给零，所以你看到这个
2 to give zeros so do you see that this
是这些人在RN
is are these guys are in RN
所以这是第一个喜欢得到的东西
so that's the first like get things
在RM2的RN2空间中直接2个空格
straight 2 spaces in RN 2 spaces in RM
那么接下来我要问的是什么
now then what am I going to ask about
这些空间我想我已经开始了
these spaces I guess I already started
询问并没有等待答案
asking and didn't wait for an answer
它们的尺寸因此具有尺寸R.
their dimension so this has dimension R
什么是这个维度有多少
and what's the dimension how many this
如果我有M，那真的是一个关键的事实
is really such a key fact if I have M
方程式ax等于零，如果R为
equations ax equals zero and if R of
那些方程是独立的有多少
those equations are independent how many
解决方案所以空间的维度
solutions so the dimension of the space
我会告诉我有多少解决方案
is going to tell me how many solutions
把X分成两个M方程但是真的
to X into two M equations but really
只是真正的独立方程
only are genuine independent equations
在这个系统中，ax等于零
in in this system ax equals zero
我可以再次提出多少问题
how many so can I ask the question again
我希望得到答案
and I want the answer in terms of
M和n是我所拥有的我真的拥有我们的
M and n are so I have I really have our
方程式，如果我看到ax等于0它
equations if I look at a x equals 0 it
看起来像M个单独的方程式，但是
looks like M separate equations but but
M减去R只是副本或
M minus R of those are just copies or
其他人的组合也是如此
combinations of others so there are
独立方程式那么多少
independent equations so what how many
我得到了，这就是我要写的东西
of I got and that's what I'm gonna write
在这里是的所以是啊所以X有X有n
in here yeah so yeah so X has X has n
组件，你知道真的
components and there are real you know
他们必须要有效的方程式
active equations that they have to
满足
satisfy
并留下n-R这是关键
and that leaves n minus R that's the key
指出那是关键点
point that's the key point that there
是N且X的部件在未知
are n components of X and unknowns in
未知并且存在约束
unknowns and there are are constraints
独立约束所以那些n
independent constraints so the those n
如果我想满足那些，你就会得到
you get if I want to satisfy those
敲出尺寸R的约束
constraints that knocks out dimension R
和叶子和减去R所以这是
and leaves and minus R so that's the
这里的尺寸和美的
dimension here and the beauty of the
帐户是这两个数字相加的
account is that those two numbers add up
对每个人都占了一席之地
to n everybody's accounted for every
矢量在行空间中有一块和
vector has a piece in the row space and
零空间中的一块，那就是
a piece in the null space and that's
有两件让你回来了
there was two pieces give you back the
矢量你看到，这是刚刚好
vector do you see that that's just nice
这些数字出来的权利和
that the numbers come out right and of
当然他们也在这里出来
course they come out right here too you
可以说只是转置一个矩阵和
could say just transpose a matrix and
便又同样的事情写出来
write it right the same thing again
列空间的维度是多少
what's the dimension of the column space
等于矩阵的列空间
equals the column space of the matrix
尺寸R右
has dimension R right
和行这这家伙冷落
and the row this this guy is left out of
一些线性代数书就像它一样
some linear algebra books as if it like
它不属于
it doesn't belong but
并且他们清楚你知道没有它
and they clear that you know without it
一切都只有3/4ders完成了我们
everything is of only 3/4 ders done we
必须有这个家伙和它的维度
have to have this guy and it's dimension
艾玛-是的，是的，是的
is Emma - yeah it's yeah that count is
只是为了转置这个计数是什么
just for a transpose what this count was
是的，所以我们有这些尺寸
for a yeah so we've got those dimensions
为n减去RR和M-是啊你，你
are n minus R R and M - yeah you you
知道你会知道这一点，但我们需要
know you'll have known this but we need
我们之前在2018年再次看到它
to see it once again in 2018 before we
现在就开始使用它了
start using it now is that the
基本定理是，所有的一切-它
fundamental theorem is that all all - it
是不是还有另一块
is no there's another piece to the
基本定理，这是你的一种
fundamental theorem which is sort of you
可以说这里的几何形状我有一个
could say the the geometry here I have a
子空间在这里我有这样一个子空间
subspace here I have a subspace of this
大的n维空间所以我想象
big n-dimensional space so I visualize
那些子空间作为某种平面
those subspaces as some kind of a plane
R维平面和N减R
an R dimensional plane and an N minus R
维平面，我想看看如何
dimensional plane and I want to see how
这两架飞机是如何相连的
are those two planes connected how are
这两个主张相互关联，让我
those two claims connected and let me
得到一块空白的
get a piece of the blank piece of the
董事会要记住最后一步吧
board to remember the final step right
所以我们得到了尺寸R和n-R和
so we've got dimensions R and n - R and
然后在这里R和M减去R好吧
then over here R and M minus R okay this
是用于null的行
is for the rows this is for the null
空间，所以这在它这个行
space so this has the rows in it this
将ax等于的解为空
has the null the solutions to ax equals
零什么是美丽的几何
zero what is the beautiful geometry that
你如何想象这两个空间
how do you visualize those two spaces
你如何形象化让我采取一个
how do you visualize let me take an
例
example
但一个B124248很抱歉，
but a B 1 2 4 2 4 8 sorry about that
你看，这是一个勾结的例子，所以这个
you see it's a hooked up example so this
是2乘3所以有3是什么在
is 2 by 3 so there n is 3 what's in the
这个矩阵的零空间我可以
null space of this matrix can I can you
看到一个解决ax等于0的向量
see a vector that solves a x equals 0
事实上会有多少
and in fact how many will there be
什么是我们这个矩阵的东西
what's yeah what's our for this matrix
只是告诉我所有的好东西
just tell me all the good stuff for that
例子M是2并且是3并且R是11
example M is 2 and is 3 and R is 1 1
每个人都看到一行排名
everybody sees one for the rank the rows
是依赖它只有一个
are dependent it's there's only one
列是独立的行
independent row the columns are
依赖只有每一列
dependent there's only like every column
是一个的倍数-它是排名第一
is a multiple of one - it's a rank one
矩阵确定怎么样所以它是行
matrix ok what about it so it's row
空间的维度为1，它为空
space has dimension 1 and it's null
空间的大小为22所以cuzn减去R.
space has dimension 2 2 so cuz n minus R
将是2，所以我找了几个
will be 2 so I'm looking for a couple of
两个都给0的载体我相信
vectors that both give 0 I believe
我认为我只有一个
they're I think I've only got one
独立排在那里，所以我应该
independent row there so I should be
能够找到两个不同的向量
able to find two different vectors that
是解决斧头等于0有啥
are that solve ax equals 0 so what's a
ax的解决方案等于00910减21
solution to ax equals 0 0 91 0 minus 2 1
是的，有效，有什么
yeah that works and what's an
0的独立解决方案我不扔
independent solution for 0 I don't throw
我和0和
me off for 0 and
-是的，看起来很好看
- one yeah that looks good that looks
好
good
然后声称是每一个
and then the claim is that every
解决方案将是这些的组合
solution would be a combination of those
二，这就是有多少
two and that this is how many there are
现在这是我正在完成的几何体
and now it's the geometry I'm completing
所以我们有像在此留下2分钟
so we have like two minutes left in this
讲座你只需要告诉我如何
lecture you just have to tell me how
这些之间的关系是什么
what's the relation between the these
在行空间和那个人的家伙
guys in the row space and that guy in
零空间是什么关系
the null space what's the relation
在a行和解决方案之间
between the rows of a and the solutions
如果你看到它之间的ax等于零
to ax equals zero between if you see it
如果你在那个向量中看到了那个向量
if you saw that vector in that vector
好吧，现在X是零，那么是什么呢
well a times X is zero now so what does
告诉我们
that tell us
那么我们看到了什么呢？
well what do we see for the for the
他们之间的关系是124和0-21
relation between 1 2 4 and 0 - 2 1 they
是正交的，是正交的
are orthogonal terrific yes orthogonal I
通过点积测试0-44加0
test by the dot product 0 - 4 4 add to 0
是的，所以那是完全的
yes so so the and that's a completely
当我看到ax等于0时的一般事实
general fact when I look at ax equals 0
它告诉我X是正交的
it's telling me that X is orthogonal to
你看到那些行吗？
the rows did you see that
如果我看的话，你就把它放在这里
you just put it in again here if I look
在axa有一堆行X有一个
at ax a has a bunch of rows X has one
列，我得到零，这是重点
column and I get zeros that's the point
零空间和那个等式是
of the null space and that equation is
只是说第1行是正交的
just say that Row 1 is orthogonal
因为这是第1行的点积
because that's the dot product of Row 1
有了X所以这里的第1行第2行超过3和
with X so here's Row 1 Row 2 over 3 and
第4行用X得到X行
Row 4 with X the rows with X and I get
零，所以重点是这两个
zeros so the point is then these two
空间是90度角，即a
spaces are at 90 degree angles that's a
这四个人真的很整洁
really a neat picture of the four
子空间和这两个是相同的
subspaces and these two are for the same
M中90度角偏离的原因
reason at 90 degree angles off in M
三维空间，所以这是这是
dimensional space so this is this is the
基本定理
fundamental theorem
线性代数看到的
of linear algebra to see that the
尺寸出来正确和
dimensions come out right and the
几何是正确的，然后是
geometry comes out right yeah and then
现在下次跟着笔记和我
now next time following the notes and I
拥有的的几个副本
have a few more copies of the of the
一只手伸出手，我们就会动弹
hand that one hand out will we'll move
下周快速到特征值和
on quickly next week to eigenvalues and
positive definite matrices good this is
正定矩阵这是好的
真正的线性代数继续前进
really linear algebra moving on